

Mohamed Mhiri

+216-58-11-53-44 · mohamad.elmhiri@gmail.com ·

in www.linkedin.com/in/mhiri-5



Tunis - Tunisia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full-stack software engineer with 6+ years of experience working in both full-time and part-time jobs, and 1+ year of experience as a product architect assistant.

Experienced in coding, software design, software architecture, software testing.

Possessing extensive knowledge of various technologies including Javascript, Vuejs, Nodejs, C#, .NET, MongoDB, SQL.

KEY COMPETENCIES

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Vuejs, Nodejs, Expressjs, C#, .Net, .Net Core, Java, Spring, PHP, Laravel, Python, Django, Flask

Software Design, Software Testing, Code Quality, DevOps, Containerization, Docker, Sonarqube, Azure, Nginx

MongoDB, SQL, Sql Server, Mysql, MariaDB, Oracle DB, Postgresql

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Fullstack Developer - Leadfox

Jul 2023 - Nov 2024

- Advocated for the importance of automated testing across the team.
- Developed and validated features using Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, vue/test-utils, Jest, and 5+ e2e tests using
- · Reduced human error by migrating Excel-based processes into intranet features for the marketing and content creation teams.
- Automated intranet data updates using Stripe webhooks, ensuring up-to-date and accurate information.
- Improved pages consistency by standardizing layouts with Bootstrap and CSS.

SKILLS: Front-end Development, Back-end Development, Software Testing, Vuejs, Nodejs, Expressjs, Playwright, Vue/testutils, Bootstrap, CSS, JIRA, Github, Figma.

Senior Frontend Developer - Dayshape

Jan 2022 - Mar 2023

- Improved the product maintainability, testability and performance by migrating 10+ web components from angular.js v1.8 to vue.js v2.6
- Developed and tested new product features using vue.js v2.6, Cypress v12, vue-test-utils, jest, .NET Framework v4.8
- Participated in Scum ceremonies and made 30+ code reviews

SKILLs: Front-end Development, Test Driven Design, Unit Testing, end-to-end Testing, Vuejs, Javascript, Bootstrap, Vue-Test-Utils, Jest, Cypress, .Net Framework, C#, JetBrains Rider, SCRUM, JIRA, Figma.

Senior Software Engineer - Mantu

May 2020 - Dec 2021

- Contributed in the product vision
- Designed a Distributed System
- · Documented the technical decisions
- Improveed the applications performance, maintainability, securability, modularity and testability
- Assisted technical team with issues needing technical expertise or complex systems knowledge.

SKILLs: Negociation, Communication, Software Design, Software Architecture, JQuery, Vuejs, .Net Core, .Net Framework .NET Standard, .NET Core, EntityFramework, EntityFramework Core, SQL Server.

Software Engineer - Mantu

Nov 2018 - Apr 2020

- Designed and Developed in .NET Core v3.1, Sql Server v16
- Followed TDD (Test driven Development) process with XUnit v2.4
- Created actionable dashboards with Power BI, M query language and Dax

- Prepared the CI/CD pipelines in Azure DevOps
- Wrote 10+ Documents (Wikis, Guidelines, Articles), Presented and Followed up with the Engineering team
- Analyzed and made benchmarks for 40+ market tool and Test Azure Monitor, Splunk, ELK (Elasticsearch, Logstash and Kibana) and Graylog.

SKILLs: JAMstack, DDD, TDD, microservices, Documenting, DevOps, CI, CD, Observability, SCRUM, .NET Core v3.1, .NET Framework, C#, Vuejs, Vuetify, Vuex, Javascript, Sql Server v16, Nodejs, XUnit v2.4, PowerBl, Azure Monitor, Application Insights, ELK, Graylog.

Software Engineering Internship - Kyalis Tech

Mar 2018 - Sep 2018

- Created a scalable and resilient system where individual services can communicate with each other without any central coordination
- Built a robust and reliable email system that can handle large volumes of messages and ensure delivery without any data
- Defined and managed the different steps of a process, handled exceptions and errors, and ensured data consistency across different services

SKILLs: Microservices choreography, Event based microservices, Orchestrated Saga, Apache Kafka, NodeJs, Express, Camunda, NodeMailer, Kafka-Node.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Internship supervisor -Part-time- SUDOTEK

2 months

- Guiding, assisting and providing necessary training to the team
- Following up with the team on a daily basis
- Preparing, presenting and putting in action the product roadmap

SKILLs: Leadership, Communication, Software architecture

Full Stack Developer -Part-time- Tunpack Machinery

8 months

- Developing marketing strategies to promote products and services
- Delivering 20+ features through a user-friendly web application
- Managing and administrating products/services using an intuitive administrator panel
- Providing company contact information for seamless communication and support
- Designing, developing, testing 2 websites: https://tunpackmachinery.com and https://www.tunpackpaper.com and tunpack-support the mobile app with it's administrator panel

SKILLs: nodejs, expressjs, mongodb, vuejs, ovh, ubuntu server, onrender, heroku, atlas mongodb

Full Stack Developer -Part-time- ALOULOU Optic

6 months

- Collecting, processing, and storing data from Excel sheets
- Generating financial forms and documents
- Maintaining data consistency and integrity
- · Compiling comprehensive sales statistics and historical data
- Restricting edit and delete access exclusively to the administrator
- Designing, Developing and Maintaining 5 versions of the product

SKILLs: Vuejs v3, Typescript, NodeJs, Express, MongoDB, Angular, React, Vanilla Javascript, Webpack, Ecmascript, NuxtJs, Jquery, Css, Bootstrap, Semantic-UI, Spring Boot, Java, Linux and Windows scripting.

Software Architect -Part-time- DIGITAL ATTRACTION Medical

1 month

- Researching and evaluating technical standards and tools for a project
- Testing tools, bench-marking and checking the feasibility of the solution
- Documenting the decision and presenting the result of each research by weekly

SKILLs: Software Design, Benchmark, Testing, Development, Presentation, Negociation, Writing

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATIONS

Software Engineering Student, 2015 - 2018

National Institute of Applied Sciences and Technologies

Integrated Preparatory Cycle, 2013 - 2015

National Institute of Applied Sciences and Technologies INSAT

Exam 486: Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications MTA: HTML5 Application Development Fundamentals -Certified 2017 LPIC-1102

LPIC-1 101